(シズネ)綱手様！
Lady Tsunade!
We have received a message
from the Fire Temple.
(シズネ)火ノ寺よりの伝令です！
It seems all four of the hidden tombs
have been violated.
４つの隠し墓
すべて暴かれたと…！
(綱手)やられたな…。
それで 現在の状況は？
They got us...
So what's the present situation?
Team Kakashi is
on the way right now.
(シズネ)はい 今
カカシ班が向かっています！
I see...
そうか… 敵は ただの
墓荒らしではないらしいという➡
Yamato sent a report saying
the enemies probably
aren't just grave robbers.
報告を ヤマトがよこしたが…
当たったわけだ。
So he was right.
Yes...
(シズネ)ええ… とすると
賊の狙いは…。
Then what are the thieves after?
守護忍十二士に選ばれた➡
Probably the bodies themselves
of the exceptional Shinobi
who were members of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
優秀な忍たちの遺体
そのものだろうな…。
先だっての襲撃に続いて
嫌な感じですね…。
I have a bad feeling about this,
it's all happening right
after that other attack.
暁の動きも
本格化しているというのに➡
And the activities of the Akatsuki
are shifting into high gear.
And developments
regarding Orochimaru,
行方をくらました
大蛇丸の動向も気になります。
who has hidden himself,
are a concern as well.
それに…。
And...
You mean Danzo?
ダンゾウのことか？
はい… サイを カカシ班に残すことは➡
Oh, yes...
Leaving Sai on Team Kakashi
was our request as well.
こちらの要望でも
あったわけですが➡
それを ダンゾウが
すんなり承諾したのには➡
But isn't there something behind
why he agreed without any fuss?
何か裏があるのではないかと…。
There are piles of causes
for concern everywhere we turn.
どこを向いても 不安材料が
てんこ盛りというわけだ。
But we should probably
pluck the seeds of trouble...
だが 災いの種は
摘んでおくべきだろう。
まずは 手の届くところからな。
and we start with
what's within close reach.
それでは…！
Then what do we do?
Shizune! Assign everyone
who's not supporting the Foundation
シズネ！ 今すぐ 根の息の
かかってない者を➡
to the surveillance of Danzo!
ダンゾウにつけろ！
(シズネ)はい！
Yes, ma'am!
I have a favor to ask.
((サイ : １つ お願いがございます。
(ダンゾウ)願いだと？
(サイ)はい…。
A favor, you say?
Yes...
(サイ)この名のまま しばらく➡
I would like to ask you to
keep me in Team Kakashi
(カカシ班に身を置かせては
いただけないでしょうか？))
under this name for a while.
《ダンゾウ : この笑い顔は…》
That smile on his face...
《綱手め…
今さら 何を探っておる。
Damn that Tsunade...
What is she prying into now?
Oh well...
まあいい…
しょせん 我が掌の中…》
When all is said and done,
it's all in the palm of my hand.
A New Enemy
(ヤマト)この方向は 隠し墓のある
方向とは違うのでは？
This isn't the same direction
as the hidden tombs.
(地陸)賊は 重い棺桶ごと
遺体を運んでいるが➡
The thieves are carrying
heavy coffins, body and all.
火ノ寺を中心に 玄武 青龍 白虎の
方角は険しい崖に囲まれている。
The east, west and north directions
with the Fire Temple at the center
are surrounded by steep cliffs.
(地陸)棺桶をかついで
隣国へ抜けるとしたら➡
If they are trying to escape to
the neighboring land carrying the coffins,
朱雀の方向しかない。
the only direction is South.
なるほど！
I see.
((ソラ : オレの力がよ うっとうしい》
My power is a nuisance.
((でもな…。
But nuisance or not,
I can't throw it away.
(うっとうしくても
この力を捨てることは できねえ))
Because I must have revenge
on the one who killed my father.
((オレの父さんを…
殺したヤツに復讐するために))
おい お前！
なに 人の顔見てんだよ！
Hey, what're you looking at?!
Oh!
You mentioned revenge, didn't you?
(ナルト)
お前さぁ 復讐って言ってたな…。
チッ …ふん！
Oh...
なんだ？ えらく見晴らしの
いいところへ 出ちまったけど…。
Oh... We came out to a place
with a great view.
But the enemy
won't show up here.
(サクラ)これじゃ 敵も現れないわね。
そうだよな…
隠れるところもねえし…。
That's right...
There's nowhere to hide.
ナルト！
なんだ？
Naruto!
Hm? What is it?
あそこ。
うん？
Down there...
あ!! ソラ あれ見ろ あれ あれ!!
Oh, Sora! Look down there,
down there!
Shut up! I can see it!
うるせぇ!! 見えてるよ!!
間違いない あれは…。
No doubt about it.
Those are...
えぇ 盗まれたご遺体に
間違いなさそうですね。
Those definitely seem to be
the stolen bodies.
しかし… なぜ
あんな中途半端な運び方を？
But why are they transporting them
in such crude fashion?
まるで わざと目立つように…。
It's as if they're attracting
attention on purpose.
《…罠か？ だとしたら➡
Is it a trap?
If it is, then perhaps
they're targeting...
狙いは おそらく…》
このままじゃ
逃げられちまうってばよ！
They're going to
get away at this rate!
Captain Yamato!
(サクラ)ヤマト隊長！
地陸さんは ここに。
Chiriku, please wait here and
contact the Fire Temple,
万が一の場合 火ノ寺との
連絡をお願いします。
just in case something happens.
承知。
ナルトと ソラ君は まっすぐ追え。
Got it.
Naruto and Sora,
you guys pursue head on!
サクラと サイは 左手より
ボクは 右手に回り 援護する。
Sakura and Sai will follow from the left,
and I will wrap around to the right
and provide back-up.
Hey... Why do I have to
go with him?!
ちょ… なんで コイツと!?
Sending you alone
would be a concern.
キミだけじゃ 心配だ。
Besides, Sora looks to be
quite dependable.
それに ソラ君は
なかなか頼りになりそうだしね。
《…なるほど。
I get it. I read in a book that
one poison drives out the other.
「毒をもって 毒を制す」か。
本で読んだ》
Oh!
むぅ… あっ！
コラッ 待て!!
Hey, wait up!
待てってばよ！
Hold it!
Let me tell you one thing.
言っとくけど オレだって
お前みたいな バチ当たりは➡
I'm tired of being around
a repulsive guy like you!
願い下げだぜ！
うるせぇよ！
Shut up!
If Captain Yamato decided on this,
then we have no choice, right?!
ヤマト隊長が 決めたんなら
仕方ねえだろ！
Then you just stay behind me
and keep quiet!
なら オレの後ろで
おとなしくしてろ！
This is a Fire Temple matter!
これは 火ノ寺の役割だ！
You back-talking jerk!
この…！ 減らず口野郎が～！
I'm going on ahead.
お先に。
野郎！
Jerk!
Heh...They fell for it.
(フリド)フッ… かかったな。
There's nothing here for us to
protect ourselves with if this is a trap.
もし 罠だとしたら
ここじゃ 防ぐものがないわ！
いや 条件は 敵も同じだよ。
The conditions should be the same
for the enemy, too.
近づけば
遠くから確認できてしまう。
We should be able to locate them
from a distance if they approach.
《ヤマト : ４人の遺体を奪うことが
目的なら➡
If their objective is to steal
the four bodies,
罠をはる意味がない。
there's no point in setting a trap.
…なぜ わざわざ
こんなことを？》
Why are they going to
the trouble of doing such a thing?
うわっ！
Didn't I tell you?!
さっきも言ったろ
お前は おとなしく➡
I told you to stay behind me,
keep quiet, and just watch!
オレの後ろで見物してろって！
またまた
お先に 失礼しちゃうってばよ！
Excuse me while
I go on ahead again.
調子にのるな！
Don't get so full of yourself!
いってえな…。
Ow!
ソラ いい加減に…。
Sora! Knock it off.
何やってんの？ ２人とも。
What're you two doing?!
あっ 棺桶が 地面の中に。
The coffins went underground.
バチ当たりが 邪魔しなきゃ
１個だけでも取り戻せたのにな。
And here I could've gotten
at least one of them back
if this rotten guy hadn't interfered.
足引っ張ったのは テメエだろ！
You're the one
who got in the way!
What?! This time I'll give you
a posthumous name for sure!
(ソラ)なに？ 今度こそ
本当に 戒名つけてやろうか？
That's just what I want!
あぁ 上等だ。
その前に オメエの戒名選びやがれ！
Before that, hurry up and
pick one for yourself!
Cut it out, you two!
アンタたちやめなさいよ！
This isn't the time to be fighting
amongst ourselves.
今は 仲間割れ
してるときじゃないでしょ！
That's strange...
おかしいな。
(ヤマト)あらゆる気配が消えた。
All signs of the enemy's
presence has vanished.
(フリド)久しぶりだな。
待ちわびた 火ノ国の夜明けだ。
It's sure been a long time.
Oh, how long I've waited for
the dawn of the Land of Fire.
This isn't the time for you guys
to be dying.
お前ら 死んでる場合じゃないぜ。
(フリド)偶然とは
粋な計らいをしてくれるものだな。
Unexpected circumstance is something
that sets up a good arrangement.
(フリド)それとも お前らが
呼び寄せてくれたのかな？
Or did you guys
do the summoning?
フドウ フエン フウカ。
(３人)はっ！
Fudo, Fuen, Fouka!
Yes, sir...
私は ヤツにちょいと挨拶してくる。
I'm going to say hello to him.
お前たちは
他のヤツらの相手をしてやれ。
You guys take care of the others.
(フドウ)はっ。
(フエン/フウカ)はい。
Yes, sir!
(フエン)これが設計図。
壊さずに運んでよ。
This is the design diagram.
Move it without destroying it, okay?
一世一代の傑作。
完璧なできなんだから。
It's a once-in-a-lifetime masterpiece
of perfect quality.
(フドウ)ハッ！ 偉そうに。
Acting like you're so big.
土地を運んでくるのは このオレだ。
I'm the one who has
to do the moving.
いくら傑作でも
運んでこなきゃ タダの落描きだ。
Masterpiece it may be.
But it's nothing but scribbling
if I don't move it.
(フエン)フフフッ… 知らないの？
Don't you know?
浮世絵だって 名が残るのは
板彫る人間じゃなくて➡
With woodblock prints,
the one who lives on in history
is the artist who created the design,
下絵を描いた絵師なのよ。
not the one
who did the carving.
なにっ？
What?!
(フウカ)口数の多い男は嫌われるよ。
Nobody likes men who talk too much.
Just get started.
さっさと始めなさい。
でないと もと守護忍十二士の
フリドに しめられちゃうわよ。
Or Furido, a former member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
will strangle you.
チッ。
おぉ 怖っ。
Ooh, that's scary.
Then, I'm counting on you, Fudo.
なら 頼むわ フドウ。
あぁ やってやらぁ！
Fine, I'll do it.
(フドウ)土遁 有為転変！
Earth Syle: Impermanence!
これは何だ？
What's...this?!
サイ！
Sai!
忍法 超獣偽画！
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
これは…!?
What is this?
(地陸)土遁で
これほどの地質変化が…？
This much geological change
with Earth Style?
うわっ…。
どうやら 誰かさんのせいで
仏罰が当たったみたいだな。
It seems we've received
divine retribution
thanks to a certain someone.
そんなこと言ってる場合じゃ…。
This isn't the time to be
saying that kind of...!
サクラちゃん！
おい 待て！
Sakura!
Hey, wait!
このまま
押しつぶそうという魂胆か…。
So the true intention is to
crush me like this, huh?
《上に登るまでは
待ってはくれないだろうな…》
They probably won't wait for me
to climb up to the top.
ならば…。
If so...
木遁の術。
Wood Style Jutsu!
ずいぶんと 大がかりな罠を
仕掛けてきたもんだな…。
They sure set quite the large-scale trap.
そうか。 それでサイと離れ離れに…。
I see. So you and Sai ended up
getting separated.
気がつくと
ヤマト隊長の姿もなかった。
And before I knew it,
Captain Yamato was gone, too...
これだけの規模の地形を
変化させることのできる土遁使い。
If we're dealing
with an Earth Style user
who can alter terrain to
this great a scale,
だとしたら あなどれない敵だわ。
then it's an enemy
we can't take lightly!
とにかく 早く
みんなを探すってばよ。
Anyway, we've got
to find the others quick!
おい。
うん？
Hey...
ここ… 谷じゃなかったか？
えっ？
Didn't this used to be a valley?
(サクラ)何？ これ…。
What's this?
いつの間に… 幻術か？
Just like that?
Is this a Genjutsu?
きっと 罠よ。
I bet it's a trap.
なら 試してみるってばよ。
Then let's test it out.
Huh...?
ちょっと ナルト！
うかつに近づかないほうが…。
Hey, Naruto, don't get careless.
You'd better stay away.
ヘッ… 大丈夫だってばよ。
Heh, no problem.
とりあえず 本物の地面みたいだ。
きっと マヌケな野郎で➡
It seems, more or less,
to be solid ground.
The guy who did this
is probably a moron,
ここだけ作り忘れて慌てて作っ…。
he forgot to create this part here
and rushed to finish the job...!
ナルト!!
Naruto!
あっさり 罠に
引っ掛かりやがって…。
He got caught
in the trap just like that.
すぐに ナルトを捜しに… ア～ッ！
We've got to find
Naruto right away.
《とりあえず 上空から
全体を見渡してみるか》
I guess for now
I'll try making a sweep of
the entire area from up in the sky.
《外に出させないつもりか？》
They're not going to
let me out of here.
(フエン)ホホホホホホ…。
(フエン)そんな ヤワな術じゃ➡
There's no way you can
escape from my masterpiece
私の傑作からは
逃げられっこないよ。
with a puny Jutsu like that.
(フドウ)しかし オレたちの術から
生きのびるとはな。
I never thought
you'd survive our Jutsu.
オレの術は完璧だったしな。
My Jutsu was perfect.
フエンの設計施工のつめが
甘かったんだろうぜ。
Fuen probably didn't follow through
with the execution of her design.
まさか 木遁!?
Don't tell me that's the Wood Style.
何者だ!? お前！
Who are you?
何者って
それは こっちのセリフだよ。
"Who are you?"
That's my line.
遺体を盗んで どうするつもりだ？
What do you intend to do
by stealing those bodies?!
(フドウ)フン… これから死にゆく者に
話す必要はないな。
It's not necessary to tell someone
who's about to die.
では 力ずくでも話してもらうよ。
Then I'll have to get you
to talk by force.
フッ… オレと 力比べを
しようってのか？ ムダ ムダ！
Heh! You want to get into
a contest of strength with me?
That's futile!
土遁 蟻地獄！
Earth Style: Inescapable Suffering!
(フドウ)アハハハハ！
あっけないのう 木遁使い。
What a disappointing
Wood Style user!
I get the feeling it's kind of
a waste disposing of you, but...
始末するには ちょっと
もったいない気もするが…。
面倒だな。 やはり オレには
直接攻撃が 性に合ってる。
What a pain.
Sure enough, direct attacks
are more up my alley.
うぉ～っ！
オレの拳は
避けるだけじゃ防ぎきれないぜ。
You can't fully guard against
my fist by just dodging.
どこだ？ ここ…。
Where are we?
(サクラ)わからないけど…。 ナルトは？
I don't know...
But where's Naruto?
(ソラ)一緒に落ちたはずなのに
気配がない。
I thought we all dropped together.
I don't feel his presence here.
(サクラ)とりあえず
捜しに行かなくちゃ。
For the time being,
we have to go find him.
(ソラ)どうやら 敵は オレたちを
バラバラにさせたいらしいな。
It seems the enemy
wants to separate us.
イテテテテ…。
Ow-ow-ow-ow...
サクラちゃんたち
どこにいるんだってばよ…。 ん？
Where are
Sakura and the others?
また 分かれ道かよ…。
Another fork in the road?
う～ん…。
こっちだ！
ヘッ！ 二度も落ちてたまるかよ。
ということは
こっちの道が正解ってことか。
(フウカ)そっちじゃないよ。
ん？
えっ!? うわ～っ!!
こんなふざけた罠で
やられるかよっと！
うわ～っ!!
ふぅ… 危なく ペシャンコだったぜ。
(フウカ)フフフフフ…。
フエンの仕掛けも
たいしたことがないね。
(ヤマト)木ノ葉の
強硬武闘派の指導者 ダンゾウ。
すでに解体された暗部養成組織
根の主任だった男で➡
失脚した今も ご意見番などに
多大な影響力を持つ。
先だっての サスケ暗殺失敗以降➡
表立った動きを
見せてはいないが➡
前回のような事態を避けるため
綱手様は ダンゾウに➡
監視をつけることを決定した。
確かに サイを カカシ班に
残したことには 疑問が残る。
優秀な根の構成員で その実力を
高く買っていた サイを➡
あのダンゾウが
ただ手放すとは 考えにくい。
理由があるとすれば
人柱力である ナルトの➡
監視なのか それとも…。
残念だが サイが再び ダンゾウの指令で
動くこともないとはいえない。
まぁ 当分は
ボクも気が抜けそうにないな。